PREENA MONCY

85 Joan Dr., New City, NY 10956 | H: 8452900895 | C: 8455379810 | preenajoel@gmail.com

Summary

A goal driven Human Resources Manager highly effective at incorporating creative leadership skills and personnel management expertise to achieve business objectives. Pivotal strengths include crisis management/problem solving capabilities, communication skills, mentoring competency and managerial proficiency. Extremely passionate and committed towards work, detail oriented and can translate business strategies into HR actions that drive business results. Have previously performed business development, strategic planning, crisis management, employee training and advancement, international client development, presentations and other marketing events.

Highlights

- Hiring and Retention
- Training and Development
- Recruiting
- Employee Relations
- Labor Agreement
- Personnel Records Maintenance
- New Hire Orientation
- Exceptional Interpersonal Skills and Highly Innovative
- Excellent Work Ethics
- Auditing
- Implementing Strategies
- Team Building
- MS Office

Experience

HR & Compliance Manager (July 2017 - Present)

Westchester Family Care, Inc. Mamaroneck, NY

- Hiring and Retention
- Interviewing the Applicants
- ♣ HR Compliance Documentation like I-9 and W-4
- Criminal Background Check and Reference Check
- Mentoring and Strategic Personnel Development
- Implementing Performance Management System

- Employee Welfare and Grievance Handling
- Conducting Orientation and Onboarding
- Payroll Administration and Processing
- Personnel Data Management
- Running Compliance Reports and Ensuring Employee Compliance
- Auditing Personnel and Medical Files
- Employee Training
- Strategic Workforce Development
- Leadership Team Member

HR Assistant Manager

(February 2017 – June 2017)

Café Spice GCT, Inc. New Windsor, NY

- Hiring
- Conducting Preliminary Interviews
- Employee Retention
- Screening Applicants
- Payroll Administration and Processing (ADP)
- Worker's Compensation
- Grievance Handling
- Formulating Policies and Procedures
- Orientation and On-boarding
- Personnel Data Management
- Employee Manual Formation and Editing

HR Assistant

(November 2016 – February 2017)

Village of Mamaroneck, Mamaroneck, NY

- Workers compensation analysis
- Filing compensation claims
- HR strategy development and implementation
- Revamping and developing the employee handbook
- Suggesting and incorporating new and better policies and programs for empowering and engaging the employees
- Assisting the Village Officer

International Relations and Business Development/HRM (2009 – 2011)

Santa Monica Overseas Studies and Placements Pvt. Ltd. Cochin, Kerala, India

 Advised managers on organizational policy matters and recommended changes/transformation.

- Served as a link between management and employees by handling questions, interpreting and administering contracts and helping resolve work-related problems.
- Developed business with innovative ideas and increased sales.
- Led to new international client relationships.

Education

BBM, Bachelors in Business Management (2006)

Bangalore University, India

- Planned and organized many management events at the college level.
- ♣ Prepared teams and coordinated the tasks assigned efficiently bearing fruitful results.
- Attained an important position in the college student council synchronizing and managing important issues, and planning out policies.
- ♣ Handled inter-college and intra level HR crisis management issues. Participated in State level management events solving diverse and complex Human Resource problems instituting practical solutions.
- Acquired numerous awards for problem-solving and case management events.
- Achieved awards for various marketing events, organized by the management schools in India.
- Delivered numerous speeches and presented many power point presentations to a variety of audiences.
- Wrote articles in various newsletters and college magazines.

Bachelor of Science: Business, Management & Economics - International Management (2009)

Empire State College, NY, US

- Successfully participated in the Contract Negotiation Exercise (Course: Labor Management Relations).
- Played an important role in the Management team.
- Undertook various research papers like; The Impact of Globalization on the Indian Society, Relationship between the Business, Government and Society of India, Impact of E-commerce on India etc., which enabled me to study the different aspects of business and society in a global environment.
- Took part in varied levels of group discussions on challenging topics with people across the globe.
- Graduated with a GPA of 4.00 and acquired Grade A in all the subjects or courses. Specialized in International Management.

Graduate Certificate Program: Human Resources Management (2016)

Empire State College, SUNY, NY, US

- ♣ Completed the program triumphantly with an A grade (GPA 4.00).
- Took various competitive courses like Managing Human Capital, High Performance Management, Strategic Human Resource Management, Performance Management and Total Rewards.
- ♣ Participated in numerous discussions, debates and presentations.
- Successfully accomplished multiple research papers pertaining to different areas of Human Resource Management.
- Explored and studied various aspects of HR.